Hey Java developers,
Writing tests for a block of code that has a lot of branches?
Like in this example of validating fields within a form.
And find yourself copying and pasting
the same test format to cover all the branches?
In these scenario, consider writing a parameterized test.
A Parameterized Test, defined with the @ParameterizedTest in JUnit 5
A Parameterized Test, defined with the ParameterizedTest annotation in JUnit 5
Is a type of test where a scenario is defined
And then a data source is defined
That passes different arguments into the scenario
Improving maintainability and expandability
Improving the maintainability and expandability
Parameterized tests can take several different data sources types
Happy Testing!